It will be brutal.
Metalocalypse: Army of the Doomstar is a animation,
comedy, music film directed by Brendon Small.
After the heroic rescue of Toki Wartooth, DETHKLOK frontman Nathan Explosion finds himself traumatized in a BRUTAL professional and romantic flat-spin all while
he is tasked with fulfilling the prophecy and confronting the ultimate songwriting challenge: write the SONG OF SALVATION and save the planet.
Can Nathan Explosion look beyond his brutally damaged ego to save his band, stop
the Metalocalypse, and finally face the ultimate evil: Salacia?
Edgar / Pickles / Nathan Explosion/ Skwisgaar / Charles /
Knubbler (voice), played by Brendon Small.
William Murderface / Toki Wartooth / Dr. Rockzo (voice), played by Tommy Blacha.
General Crozier (voice), played by Victor Brandt.
Fan (voice), played by Thundercat.
Priest (voice), played by King Diamond.
Salacia / Senator Stampingston / Oscar Explosion /
Fan (voice), played by Mark Hamill.
Metalocalypse: Army of the Doomstar is a 2023 American direct-to-video adult animated
fantasy film based on the Adult Swim animated series Metalocalypse.
The film is written and directed by series co-creator Brendon Small and is a direct
sequel to the 2013 special, Metalocalypse: The Doomstar Requiem.
The film was released on August 22, 2023, alongside
Dethklok's fourth studio album, Dethalbum IV.
The film was dedicated to longtime series director, Jon
Schnepp, who died in 2018 before production began.
The film is the third and final of Adult Swim's line of straight-to-video movies after Aqua Teen Forever: Plantasm
and The Venture Bros.: Radiant Is the Blood of the Baboon Heart, and was released by Warner Bros.
Home Entertainment.
The film picks up after the events of the Metalocalypse: The Doomstar Requiem special, with Dethklok tasked to write the "song of
salvation" in order to save the planet from impending doom, and serves as the series finale to the Metalocalypse.
The film explores themes of cartoon, heavy metal,
apocalypse, adult animation, death metal.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.